# Anadi Sharma





Bengaluru, India | +917771874555 | anadi.sky17@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/anadisharma93

### **Profile**

Passionate Software Engineer with experience in writing scripts, open source development, deployment and implementation of code, also knows modern DevOps practices. Having good communication skills & problem-solving skills and an apt to learn & grow.

# **Experience**

## SRE/PLATFORM ENGINEER, SAMSUNG R&D

#### AUG 2021 — PRESENT, BENGALURU

- Created monitoring and alerting stack for platform & applications across, in Prometheus and Grafana with PagerDuty On-call 24x7.
- Part of major migration of Samsung Ads Project across various team including Database migration, AWS resources migration & K8s migration from monolith to micro-services with 0 downtime.
- Developed CI-CD infrastructure and pipelines in K8s cluster and EC2 machines as well.
- · Responsible for maintaining, operating & optimizing data platforms like Kafka clusters, Airflow, Aerospike Database, Apache Druid etc. as an DataOps team.
- Using GitOps Model developed & maintained all the infrastructure of AWS cloud in terraform, All Kubernetes manifests are in Helm code, CI-CD system are in GHA & as Argo CD manifests in git.
- Wrote several automation scripts in bash & in GO lang e.g. notification of events like pd alerts, AWS events to slack, email; AWS Security rules analysis script in which reports open to internet rules as critical etc.
- · Part of Architecture Review Board for project across Samsung Ads giving them costs saving insight and efficient Infrastructure.
- · Wrote Technical Specification and Created AWS Cost Intelligent Dashboard-centralized dashboard to view cost, suggestions, using well architect framework.
- Reduced Deployment time using spinnaker by 75% using packer, custom ami and ansible script.
- Increase revenue of project by solving request drop issue caused by highly spiky unpredictable traffic adopting better scaling policies, Node Pools etc.
- Developed Dora-Metrics project which uses GitHub & Argo CD deployments APIs, JIRA APIs and PagerDuty APIs and pushes the DORA metrics to Grafana.

## **CLOUD/DEVOPS ENGINEER, 3K TECHNOLOGIES**

#### SEP 2020 — AUG 2021, BENGALURU

- Developed in a notification script in lambda (AWS) which inputs an AWS event and targets a slack channel notification and SNS topic.
- · Creating CI pipelines in Jenkins server/GitHub Actions. and push to repo like s3/Ifrog.
- · Created a latency script which deploys on every server and calculates latency of endpoint given using cURL.
- · Creating CD pipelines in Spinnaker/GitHub actions which deploys on AWS ASG/Kubernetes. Education

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER. MAHINDRA COMVIVA

#### NOV 2017 — JUL 2020, GURGAON

- · Worked as DevOps Engineer which includes Handling server side operations tasks, database debug in MySQL, and handling AWS infra.
- · Wrote automation scripts like a server monitoring script which monitors Disk, CPU & Memory and send alert message through email.
- Worked with different Dev teams (frontend, backend, data pipeline), product management teams with builds, deployment and production debugging.

## **Education**

B.E., Institute of Engineering & Technology, Devi Ahilya University (IET-DAVV), Indore Jul 2013 — Aug 2017

- Studied Computer Science & Information Technology which includes OOPS programing, Computer Networks, Compiler, Digital Electronics etc.
- Scored 88% & 85% in High school Diploma(10th&12th) & 72 % in Engineering degree.

## **Skills & Abilities**

- Terraform
- Kubernetes: Deployment, Helm Charts, Autoscaling, Administration, K8s
  Optimization, Operator & CRDs, Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD), Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)
- AWS: Lambda, Load Balancer, EC2, S3, Route53 etc. AWS Solutions Architect Associate Certificate
- · Agile: JIRA, Agile release, Sprints
- Monitoring & Alerts: Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, PagerDuty.

- Docker
- GO Lang: Scripting, Web Development, Rest APIs, Open source Golang projects.
- · Nginx
- CI-CD: Jenkins, Argo CD, GitHub Actions, Spinnaker
- · Linux: Shell/Bash Scripting, Networking
- · DataOps: Kafka, Aerospike DB, MySQL, Druid

## Awards, Activities and Interests

- Developed Ideas for Hackathon Events and won 3rd price for Cost Intelligence Dashboard for cost analysis in AWS.
- Got a "Catalyst Award" in Samsung Annual fest for providing creative solutions to existing business problem and breaking old age way of thinking.
- Got Spot Award in Samsung Ads for Migrating entire SSP Ads Project in Samsung with 0 Downtime and outages.
- Got "Star of Quater Award" for DORA metrics development and implementation across various projects.
- Avid book reader especially fictional works of art and also likes to journal & write.
- Enjoys daily running and YOGA, Art of Living Volunteer.